#哈喽大家好我是王刚
hi everyone, this is Wang Gang
#本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
in this video I'm gonna share with you a homely dish
#苦瓜煎蛋饼
bitter gourd fried eggs pancake
#首先我们准备苦瓜一条
first, let's prepare a bitter gourd
#用清水把苦瓜清洗干净备用
clean it with clear water
#然后将苦瓜的两头切掉
then remove the stem of bitter gourd on both sides
#从中间下刀切成两边
cut in the middle and split it in two
#然后用平刀把苦瓜籽切掉
cut off the bitter seeds in "Ping Dao" (flat cut) technique
#不会平刀切的朋友也可以用勺子刮干净
you can also use a spoon to shave the seeds off
#然后再把苦瓜切成2毫米左右的薄片备用
then cut the bitter gourd into 2 cm thin slices
#苦瓜切得越薄口感就越好
the thinner you cut the slices, the better it tastes
#这样煎出来的蛋才不会发苦
in this way, the pancake won't be bitter
#下一步我们开始处理苦瓜
next, let's fight with the bitter gourd
#首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
put some water into the wok first
#开大火把锅里面的水烧开
boil the water with strong fire
#水烧开之后加入食用盐2克
add 2g salt once the water is boiling
#加入少许的白糖
add a little sugar
#再加入适量的食用油
and the appropriate amount of cooking oil
#然后把切好的苦瓜下锅焯水30秒
then blanch the bitter gourd slices for 30 seconds
#焯水的目的是减少苦瓜的苦涩味
the purpose of blanching is to reduce the bitter taste
#加盐的目的是防止维生素流失
the purpose of adding salt is to prevent vitamin loss
#30秒之后将焯好水的苦瓜倒出
after 30 seconds of blanching, pour the bitter gourd slices out
#再用凉水冲洗之后沥干水分备用
wash them with cold water, then drain the water
#这一步的目的是把苦瓜的温度降下来防止苦瓜发黄
this is to cool the bitter gourd down and prevent them from turning yellow
#下一步我们开始处理鸡蛋
next, we prepare the eggs
#首先我们在碗中打入3个鸡蛋
first, we crack 3 eggs into the bowl
#加入适量的食用盐
add some salt
#加入少许的胡椒粉
add a little pepper
#然后用筷子把鸡蛋朝一个方向搅拌1分钟
stir the eggs with chopsticks in one direction for 1 minute
#搅拌的时候不能停
don't stop while stirring the eggs
#这一步的目的是通过快速搅拌把空气搅进蛋液里面
this is to let the air fully mixed with the eggs through fast-stirring
#只有经过这样搅拌的蛋液才能煎出色泽金黄的蛋饼
stirring like this can make sure the golden color of the pancake
#蛋液搅拌均匀后再将焯好水的苦瓜倒入蛋液中轻轻的搅拌均匀备用
mix the eggs with the bitter gourd together, and stir slightly to make sure they are fully mixed
#下一步我来跟大家分享如何煎鸡蛋饼不粘锅
next, I will show you how to avoid sticking while frying the egg
#首先我们把锅烧热至冒烟为止
heat up the wok until it smokes
#然后在锅中加入少许的油
add some oil into the wok
#把锅中的油烧热之后再加入适量的清水
add some water once the oil is heated up
#用清水把锅清洗干净之后再用此法重复一次
clean the wok with clear water, and repeat this technique one more time
#这一步骤在行业中被称为“养锅”
this technique is called "yangguo" (season the wok)
#家庭炒锅经过这样的处理之后可以杜绝99%的粘锅
the family wok has a 99% chance of not sticking after this treatment
#在第三次把锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
after heating the wok for the third time, add some oil to grease the wok
#锅滑好之后将热油倒出再加入少许的底油
after that, pour out the hot oil and add some base oil
#然后将调好的蛋液缓缓下锅
pour slowly the prepared eggs mixture into the wok
#把中间堆积的蛋液往边上摊
push the egg liquid in the middle to the side
#蛋液摊好后开微小火煎3分钟至金黄色为止
fry it with soft fire for 3 minutes until the color turns golden
#煎制的过程中需要随时摇动蛋饼
you need to shake the egg pancake all the time while frying
#这样做的目的是让蛋饼均匀受热防止煎糊
this is to let the egg pancake be heated evenly, to avoid overcooking
#微小火煎3分钟之后把蛋饼翻面过来再煎2分钟
after 3-minute fry with soft fire, flip it to the other side and fry for 2 minutes
#继续煎2分钟之后即可出锅装盘
continue frying for 2 minutes and it's ready to serve
#一道非常美味的苦瓜煎蛋就制作完成
a very delicious dish of bitter gourd fried eggs pancake is done!
#下面开始煎蛋饼的技术总结
here are some tips for you guys:
#第一，苦瓜需要切薄一些这样吃起来才不会有太重的苦味
tip1: the bitter gourd slices need to be thinly cut so that to avoid a too bitter taste
#第二，煎蛋饼全程都必须小火否则容易煎糊
tip2: use soft fire during the whole frying process or it will be overcooked
#家庭煎蛋饼之前必须“养锅”这样才能减少粘锅的几率
tip3: "yangguo" (season the wok) at first, this will reduce the chance of sticking
#煎蛋饼的技术总结完毕
tips end
#关注头条号美食作家，这里总有一款属于你
Subscribe to my channel, where there is always a dish for you~